Guide to the Beardsley Ruml Papers 1917-1960
University of Chicago Library
Ruml, Beardsley. Papers
1917-1960
7.5 linear feet (15 boxes)
Hanna Holborn Gray Special Collections Research Center University of Chicago Library 1100 East 57th Street Chicago, Illinois 60637 U.S.A.
Beardsley Ruml (1894-1960), probably best know for his "Pay - As - You - Go" income tax plan, also achieved distinction as an educator, trust administrator, business executive, and advisor to commerce, industry, education, and government, particularly in the field of financial and fiscal policy. In addition, he was a prolific writer and much in demand as a speaker, both on general subjects of social and economic interest and on his fields of specialization.
Information on Use
Access
The collection is open for research.
Biographical Note
Beardsley Ruml (1894-1960), probably best know for his "Pay - As - You - Go" income tax plan, also achieved distinction as an educator, trust administrator, business executive, and advisor to commerce, industry, education, and government, particularly in the field of financial and fiscal policy. In addition, he was a prolific writer and much in demand as a speaker, both on general subjects of social and economic interest and on his fields of specialization.
Educator and businessman. A.B., Dartmouth College, 1915. Ph.D., University of Chicago, 1917. Director, Laura Spelman Rockefeller Memorial, 1922-1929. Dean of Social Sciences, University of Chicago, 1931-1933; professor of education, 1931-1933. Treasurer, R.H. Macy and Company, 1934-1945; Chairman of the Board, 1945-1951.
Scope Note
The papers are divided into three series. Series I contains biographical material, including clippings and personal correspondence. Series II includes professional correspondence, organized alphabetically by correspondent. Also in the series are materials Ruml received as part of his work with various organization, particularly the Committee for Economic Development (CED).
Series III, Speeches and Writings contains manuscripts, reprints and associated materials and correspondence for articles, papers, memoranda and speeches Ruml wrote and delivered from 1917 through 1959. Several files concern the Pay-As-You-Go tax scheme.
Related Resources
Browse finding aids by topic.
Subject Headings
Ruml, Beardsley, 1894-1960; Income tax
INVENTORY
- Series I: Biographical Material
  - Biographical material, Biographical sketch "BR Chronology" "Memorandum of E.N. Conversation with Leon Henderson for B.R. Memoirs" Atomic Energy Control Conference List of Participants Letters re leaving the University of Chicago Correspondence Biographical clippings (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Series II: Correspondence
  - Adams-Anthony, Adams, Governor Sherman Adler, Mortimer J. Allen, James E. Alvera, Pierluigi American Council To Improve Our Neighborhoods (ACTION) Andrews, Fletcher R. Anthony, Edward (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Bane-Business, Bane, Frank Barr, Stringfellow Belgram, Jr., Frank Benton, William Berk, Harry A. Blackwell, T. E. Boeschenstein, Harold Boy Scouts of America Britt, Stuart Henderson Bronson, Howard C. Brownlow, Louis Bulova, Arde Burns, Arthur F. Business Week (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Carosi-Council, Carosi, Giuseppe Case Institute of Technology Chase, Stuart Cherne Review Committee for International Economic Growth Council on Foreign Relations, Inc. (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Cousins-Curtis, Cousins, Norman Craig, Robert S. Crowther, Geoffrey Curtis, Thomas B. (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Committee for Economic Development, Commission on Money and Credit (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Committee for Economic Development, Trustees and Executive Committees (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Committee for Economic Development, Research and Policy Committee (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Committee for Economic Development, Education Subcommittee (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - CED, Miscellaneous (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Dubinsky, David-Duke Chapter of the AAUP (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Cartmouth (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Democratic National Committee (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Earlham-Emmerick, Earlham College Eastman, Whitney Edson, Peter Edwards, Edward E. Emmerick, Herbert (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Education, 1958-1959 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Education Act (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Encyclopedia Britannica (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Encyclopedia Britannica Films (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Enterprise Paint Mfg. Co. (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Fenn College (Box 2, Folder 11-12)
  - Fisk University (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Ford Foundation; Fund for the Advancement of Education (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Gardner-Gulick, Gardner, John W. General American Investors Company, Inc. Gould, Beatrice Governor's Committee on Marketing of School Bonds Greater Doane Development Program Greater New York Fund Griffith, Charles E. Gulick, Luther (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Hale-Hutchisson, Hale, Clayton G. Hampton Trustees Harris, Seymour Hayes, Ralph Hazard, Leland Henderson, Leon Hettinger, Albert J. Hocking, William Ernest Hopkins, Ernest Martin Housing and Home Finance Agency Howe, John Humphrey, Hubert H. Hutchins, Robert M. Hutchisson, Elmer (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - International Hudson Corporation (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Javits-Junket, Javits, Jacob K. Jordon, W. K. Journal of Commerce "Junket" Brand Foods (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Jewelry Research Foundation (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Jewelers Acceptance Corporation (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Kalamazoo- Kovenetsky, Kalamazoo College Kansas State Teachers Association Keppel, Francis Kerr, Sanford Key, V. O. Kimpton, Lawrence A. Kiwanis Club Knight, Robert A. Knopf, Alfred A. Kovenetsky, Sam (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Larsen-Lubin, Larsen, Roy E. Lewis, William C. Life Look Lubin, Isador (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Manhattan-Museum, Manhattan College Mayor's Advisory Council McGrath, Earl J. Merriam, Charles E. Metropolitan Museum of Art Moses, Robert Murphy, C. H. Museum of Modern Art (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - R. H. Macy and Co., Inc. (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Market Research Corporation of America (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Museum of Modern Art (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - National-New York, National Resource Committee National Resources Planning Board New College New School for Social Research New York Institute of Technology New York University (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - National Bureau of Economic Research (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - National Citizens Council for Better Schools (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - National Planning Association (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - National Securities and Research Corporation (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Ogburn-Otten, Ogburn, Charlton Ogburn, William Fielding Organization for Trade Cooperation Orr, Dudley W. Otten, Howard (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Palmer-President's, Palmer, C. F. Parade Publications, Inc. Parents' Magazine George Peabody College for Teachers Peerless Casualty Company Pension Plans Phi Beta Kappa President's Committee on Employment of the Physically Handicapped (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Puerto Rico (Box 5, Folder 1a-1c)
  - Radio-Rudick, Radio Reports, Inc. Rauh, Morton A. Resources for the Future, Inc. Ribicoff, Abraham Rockefeller, John D. (Jr.) Rockefeller, Nelson A. Roper, Elmo Ross, Frederika Rudick, Harry J. (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Laura Spelman Rockefeller Memorial Foundation (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Schlesinger-Stouffer, Schlesinger, Arthur, Jr. Schmidt, A.W. Sears World (regarding) Shimer College Shuster, George H. (regarding) Siglienti, Stefano Silbert, Theodore H. Simon, Stanley Smith, Abbott Southgate, Donald F. Sproul, Allan Stanton, Frank Stern, Edgar B. Stevenson, Adlai Stoddard, Alexander J. Stouffer, Vernon (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Spelman Fund (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Taylor-Tuttle, Taylor, Henry C. Teachers Insurance and Annuity Association of America College Retirement Equities Fund THINK Tuttle, Edward M. (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Undergraduate-University, Undergraduate Education in International Relations United Epilepsy Association United Life and Accident Insurance Company United States Committee for German Corporate Collar Bonds University of Bridgeport (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Vassar College-VISION Incorporated (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Wagner-Wyatt, Wagner, Robert F. Wallich, Henry Weinrich, John E. Wells, Herman B. Wess, Harold B. Winn, Milton World Rehabilitation Fund Wyatt, Wilson W. (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Zellerbach, J. D.-Zinsser, John S. (Box 5, Folder 10)
- Series III: Speeches and Writings
  - "Coefficients of Diagnostic Value," Journal of Philosophy, Psychology and Scientific Methods, Vol. XIV, No. 23, November 8, 1917. (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - "The Extension of Selective Tests to Industry," The Annals of the American Academy of Political and Social Science, Philadelphia, Publication No. 1251, January 1919. (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - "Two Models Showing the Interrelation of Several Significant Correlation Variables," Psychological Bulletin, July 1919. (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - "The Need for an Examination of Certain Hypotheses in Mental Tests," The Journal of Philosophy, Psychology and Scientific Methods, Vol. XVII, No. 3, January 29, 1920. (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Miscellaneous Papers, 1920s (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - "Reconstruction in Mental Tests," Journal of Philosophy, Vol. XVIII, March 31, 1921. (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - "Notes on Applied Psychology," April 24, 1922. (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Extracts from Memoranda and Dockets, Laura Spelman Rockefeller Memorial, 1922-1926. (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - "Recent Trends in Social Science," address at dedication of Social Science Research Building, University of Chicago, December 17, 1929. (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - "Pulling Together for Social Service," address at Annual Meeting of Chicago Council of Social Agencies, Jan. 31, 1930. And The Social Service Review, Vol. IV, No. 1, March 1930. (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - "Each According to the Nature of His Own Experience," address before Social Science Research Council, Sept. 2, 1930. (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - "Observations on Trends and Opportunities in Public Administration, " (with Charles E. Merriam), October 1930. (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - "The Reconstruction Trust Project," Nov. 20, 1930. (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - "The Chicago Plan," address before American Council on Education, May 8, 1931. (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Writings, 1933, 1946, "The Nostalgic and Egoic Sentiments," American Psychological Association, Sept. 7, 1933. "Some Notes on Nostalgia," Saturday Review of Literature, June 22, 1946. (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - "Social Functions of Law and Lawyers," Association of American Law Schools, December 28, 1933. (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - "The N. R. A. and A.F. of L.," Address, November 30, 1934, Cincinnati, Ohio. (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - Memorandum written immediately after Congressional elections of 1934. (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - "Report of the Commission of Inquiry into National Policy in International Economic Relations," 1934. (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - "Confusion and Compromise in Education," Address before Conference of Radcliffe Representatives, March 6, 1936. and The Educational Record, July, 1936. (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - Macy's Training Squad, 1936-1940. (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - Proceedings of the Conference at Chateau d'Ardenne, September 20-25, 1937. (Box 6, Folder 22)
  - Education, Museums, and Schools (Box 6, Folder 23)
  - "Compensatory Fiscal Policy," September 5, 1938. (Box 6, Folder 24)
  - "The Twelve Trust Proposal," September 3, 1938. (Box 6, Folder 25)
  - National Resources Planning Board. Miami Memorandum, April 6, 1938; Warm Springs Memorandum, April 1, 1938 (Prepared with Leon Henderson and given to Harry Hopkins). (Box 6, Folder 26)
  - "Business Outlook," October 28, 1937-February 5, 1938. (Box 6, Folder 27)
  - "The Businessman's Interest in National Fiscal Policy," Paper presented at the Retailer's National Forum, Washington, D.C., May 22, 1939. (Box 6, Folder 28)
  - Memo to Harry Hopkins when Secretary of Commerce. (Box 6, Folder 29)
  - Address to Social Science Group, December 2, 1939. (Box 6, Folder 30)
  - Memorandum on Changing Form of Reporting for Distribution, November 24, 1938. (Box 6, Folder 31)
  - Executive Training Course Speech, March 18, 1940-February 24, 1936. (Box 6, Folder 32)
  - National Resources Planning Board. Memo, July 24, 1939; Memo re Youth, February 7, 1940. (Box 6, Folder 33)
  - "The Position of the Retail Industry Today," Talk at Graduation Luncheon, Tobe-Coburn School for Fashion Careers, June 6, 1940. (Box 6, Folder 34)
  - "A Postward National Fiscal Program, New Republic, February 28, 1944; "National Fiscal Policy and the Two Super-Budgets," an address before the Institute of Public Affairs, University of Virginia, June 27, 1941. (Box 6, Folder 35)
  - "Something to Shoot At," Address given to Association of Furniture Manufacturers, October 7, 1943; Steel Founders Society of America, October 11, 1943; Radio, October 16, 1943; Conference on Distribution, Boston, Mass., October 18, 1943; Dayton, June 1943; Tamiment Conference. (Box 6, Folder 36)
  - Pay-As-You-Go, News Clips, Chronology, Summary, Releases (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Pay-As-You-Go, Treasury Department (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Pay-As-You-Go, House (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Pay-As-You-Go, Senate (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Pay-As-You-Go, 1942 Speeches (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Pay-As-You-Go, 1943 Speeches. (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - "Business Organizes to Look Ahead," March 12, 1943. (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - "Business Organizes to Look Ahead, April 14, 1943. (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - "Free Enterprise and Post-War Planning," November 12, 1943. Littauer Lecture. (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - "The Challenge of Tomorrow," Economic Club of New York, November 23, 1943. (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - "Post War Fiscal Policy," Address at Saturday Non-Partisan Discussions Forum of the National Republican Club, January 8, 1944. (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - "Relation of Business, Government and Labor," Journal of Electrical Workers and Operators, October 1943. (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - "Looking Ahead," Survey Graphic, May 1943. (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - "Committee for Economic Development Pushes Post-war Planning," American Business, May 1943. (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - "Your Taxes Will Go Down," Magazine Digest, June 1944; Woman's Home Companion, December 1943. (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - "A Fighting Creed for America," N. Y. Times Magazine, June 20, 1947; Coe College, June 7, 1943; College of the City of New York. (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - "Government, Business and Values," University of Omaha Baxter Lectures - Book Form, March 25 - 26, 1943. (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - "Unfinished Business," Coe College, June 7, 1943; College of the City of New York, June 16, 1943. (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - "Goodwill at Work," Address at Goodwill Industries, March 5, 1944. (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - Testimony Before the Committee of House of Representatives on Public Buildings and Grounds, January 19, 1944. (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - "Public Works and National Fiscal Policy," Real Estate Board of New York, February 5, 1944. (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - "Federal Post War Taxation," Address before Board of Directors of the Long Island Association, October 24, 1944. (Box 8, Folder 17)
  - Writings, 1944, "A Look Ahead," American Retail Foundation, February 29, 1944; Chamber of Commerce, Troy, Marcy 7, 1944; Danbury, Connecticut, March 20, 1944. "Post War Potentials," Massachusetts Bankers Association, May 25, 1944; New Jersey Bankers Association, December 8, 1944. "Post War Planning," American Association of Advertising Agencies, New York, April 11, 1944. (Box 8, Folder 18)
  - "A Post War Fiscal Program," Investment Bankers Association, Pittsburgh, Pa., February 21, 1944. (Box 8, Folder 19)
  - "Financing the Future," National Conference on Post War Housing, Chicago, March 9, 1944. (Box 8, Folder 20)
  - "A Postwar National Fiscal Program," The New Republic, February 28, 1944. (Box 8, Folder 21)
  - "Stop Dreaming About Spending Our Way Into Prosperity," The Weekly Underwriter, May 13, 1944. (Box 8, Folder 22)
  - "What Americans Think About the Job Problem," Pabst Postwar Awards, 1944. (Box 8, Folder 23)
  - "The Aspiration for Freedom," June 18, 1944 (Box 8, Folder 24)
  - "Review of the Rest of Your Life," Saturday Review of Literature, June 24, 1944. (Box 8, Folder 25)
  - "Fiscal and Monetary Policy," National Planning Association Pamphlet, July 1944; (includes related articles and correspondence) (Box 8, Folder 26)
  - Writings, 1944-1945, Correspondence with Dudley Cates related to "Fiscal Policy and Taxation of Business," Tax Law Review, Vol. 1, No. 1, October-November, 1945; American Bar Association, September 11, 1944, 1945 "Should Corporation Taxes Be Abolished?" America's Town Meeting of the Air, December 14, 1944 "Fiscal and Economic Policy," Controller's Institute, October 2, 1944. (Box 8, Folder 27)
  - "Personal Values through Education," Regents, Albany, October 19, 1944. (Box 8, Folder 28)
  - "Taxation for Prosperity," N.J. Bankers Association, December 8, 1944. (Box 8, Folder 29)
  - "Go to School and See the World," Coronet, March 1945 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - "Public Works and Construction After the War," Chicago Building Congress, March 20, 1945; New York Building Congress, April 24, 1945 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - "Tomorrow's Business," 1945. (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - "The Protection of Individual Enterprise," The Academy of Political Science, New York, April 5, 1945; Release, April 6, 1945. (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - "Taxes After the War," Non-Partisan Forum, National Republican Club, March 31, 1945. (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - "Stabilizing the Construction Industry as an Objective of National Policy," Testimony, Special Committee to Study Problems of Small Business, May 9, 1945. (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - "Cooperation of Government and Business for Prosperity," Liberal Party, May 22, 1945. (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Testimony (Full Employment) before Senate Committee on Banking and Currency on S 380, August 24, 1945. (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Memo on "The Application of Economic and Financial Knowledge," September 5, 1945. (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - "World Trade and Peace," Address before National Foreign Trade Convention, New York City, November 14, 1945. (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - "Something to Shoot At," Address at City Club, Rochester, N.Y., November 24, 1945. (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - "Taxation for Prosperity," Address given at Fourth Annual Conference for Canadian Retailers, Toronto, January 15, 1946. (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - "Prosperity and Peace," Address before the Chestnut Street Association, Philadelphia, Pa., Reprinted for Great Island Conference, January, 1947. (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - "Tax Policies for Prosperity," Address before American Finance Association, Cleveland, Ohio; American Economic Review Proceedings, Vol. XXXVI, No. 2, May 1946. (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - Memo to the Century Group, February 18, 1946. (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - "The Taxation of Corporation Income," Conference on Taxation, University of Miami, March 27, 1946. (Box 9, Folder 16)
  - "The Budget and Fiscal Policy," Address before Pennsylvania Bankers Association, May 11, 1946. (Box 9, Folder 17)
  - "The New Tax Policy," Address before Annual Meeting of the New York Employing Printers Association, Inc., May 27, 1946. (Box 9, Folder 18)
  - "Some Notes on Nostalgia," The Saturday Review of Literature, June 22, 1946 (Box 9, Folder 19)
  - "Let's Modernize Congress," Kiwanis Magazine, July 1946. (Box 9, Folder 20)
  - "Roads to Peace," Address to the Foxhowe Association of Buck Hills Falls, Pa., July 21, 1946. (Box 9, Folder 21)
  - "Fiscal Policy for High Employment." (Box 9, Folder 22)
  - "Can Additional Taxes Combat Inflation?" CBS Broadcast, April 5, 1946. (Box 9, Folder 23)
  - "Macy's Place in the Scheme of Things," Address to Training Squad, October 2, 1946. (Box 9, Folder 24)
  - "The Place of the Construction Industry in the National Economy," Address before National Electrical Contractors Association, Atlantic City, N.J., October 17, 1946. (Box 9, Folder 25)
  - "Need We Tax Away Prosperity?" Nation's Business, November 1946. (Box 9, Folder 26)
  - "Way to Prosperity," The Iron Age, January 2, 1947. (Box 9, Folder 27)
  - "Tax Policies for Prosperity," University of Miami, April 4, 1947. Reprint, The Tax Magazine, June 1947; Commercial and Financial Chronicle, April 10, 1947. (Box 9, Folder 28)
  - Letter to Senator Ralph E. Flanders, February 19, 1947 (Box 9, Folder 29)
  - Summary of Address, University of Chicago Round Table, Washington, D.C., March 10, 1947. (Box 9, Folder 30)
  - "Eliminate Corporation Income Taxes." (Box 9, Folder 31)
  - "Let's Talk Business," Colliers, March 29, 1947. (Box 9, Folder 32)
  - "Taxes and the Budget," Address, Chamber of Commerce of the State of New York, April 10, 1947. (Box 9, Folder 33)
  - "The Next Depression," Cosmopolitan, April 1947. (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - "The Business Outlook, What Can Government Do About It?" The New York Times, May 4, 1947. (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - "Taxes, the Budget and the Debt," Address, American Bankers' Association, September 29, 1947. (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Great Island Conference, and reprints, Century Association, October 31, 1947 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - CED Statement re Public Construction vs. Relief, October 16, 1947. (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - "Aid to Europe - Can Your Afford It?" American Forum of the Air, November 25, 1947. (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Summary of Addresses, Washington, D.C., January 9, 1948, Annual Meeting of the American Retail Federation; Toledo, Ohio, February 2, 1948, Retail Merchants Annual Dinner Meeting. (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - "The Interest Rate Problem," Address, Washington Board of Trade, March 16, 1948. (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - "Thinking About the World and Its Economics," Address before Second Annual Magazine Forum of the National Association of Magazine Publishers, April 27, 1948. (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - "Public Aspects of Taxation," Summary of Address before Third National Textile Seminar, Shawneeon-the-Delaware, Pa., May 10, 1948; Address before Controllers' Congress Convention, May 27, 1948; Address before Tax Executives Institute, May 19, 1948. (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - Address before Trustees and Guests of CED, Waldorf Astoria Hotel, New York City, May 20, 1948. (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - "Taxation and Fiscal Policy," Workshop on Problems of Economic Education, Riverdale, August 1948. (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - R. H. Macy Wage Testimony, August 12, 1948. (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - "The Meaning of Freedom in Our National Economic Life," New York Herald Tribune Forum, October 19, 1948. (Box 10, Folder 14)
  - "Current Problems of Fiscal Policy," Conference of Bank Correspondents, First, National Bank in St. Louis, November 4, 1948; Annual Meeting of the American Farm Bureau Federation, Atlantic City, N.J., December 15, 1948; National American Wholesale Grocers' Association, Ambassadors Hotel, Atlantic City, N.J., January 13, 1949; Chamber of Commerce, Kansas City, Mo., December 7, 1948. (Box 10, Folder 15)
  - Council of State Governments, December 1948. (Box 10, Folder 16)
  - "What Savings Bonds Mean to Fiscal Policy," December 6, 1948 (Box 10, Folder 17)
  - "More Taxes or More Savings Bonds," Colliers, April 30, 1949 (Box 10, Folder 18)
  - "Opportunity and Duty in Puerto Rico," Address before Board of Trustees of CED, Washington, D.C., May 11, 1949. (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Bulova School of Watchmaking Address, NYU, June 11, 1949. (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Article for The Chicago Defender. (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Response by BR, New York State Council of Retail Merchants, Inc., September 17, 1949. (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - "Are We Going Broke? BR Says No." Colliers, August 20, 1949 (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - "Memo to the National Committee for Repeal of Wartime Excise Taxes," January 12, 1950; Press and Radio Releases; Statement on Wartime Excise Tax Repeal, January 21, 1950. (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Writings, 1950, "The Budget, Taxes and the Debt," Annual Stock-holders Meeting, Savings Banks Trust Company, January 18, 1950 "The New Economic Insight," American Affairs, April 1950. (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - "The Little Capitalists Get Together," Colliers, January 21, 1950 (Box 11, Folder 8)